

MD ATIKUR RAHMAN

- +358 465243555
- Ida Aalbergintie 1B 58, Helsinki, 00400, Finland
- www www.uxatik.com

PROFESSIONAL SKILL

- UI/UX design
- User research
- Wire-framing, Prototyping
- Website design
- Front-end development

</> CODING SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap
- JavaScript, ¡Query, React
- GitHub, Jira, Trello

∰ TOOLS

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe XD, Sketch
- Invision, Marvelapp

LANGUAGE

• English, Bangla, Finnish

♥ INTERESTS

- Travelling, Table Tennis
- Reading Tech blog
- Cooking,

CAREER SUMMARY

I have versatile background in design and software development. I enjoy working in a creative agile environment with multi-cultural teams. My professional interests lie in the areas of user experience, web design, front-end development, interaction design, prototyping, graphic design, fintech, and a wide range of branding along with agile project management including scrum, Kanban, and so on.

>

EXPERIENCE -

UI/UX Developer

Cesim Oy. (Helsinki) June 2018 - Dec 2018

Introduce new user interface based on exiting Cesim products. Develop the interface using the latest front-end technology (HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript). Support most common browsers and a wide range of devices for Cesim business simulations.

UI Designer

Kite Games Studio Ltd. (Dhaka) Jan 2017 – July 2017

I researched and developed new ideas based on the current trend of IOS and Android application. Delivered 6+ IOS applications, where I have used Adobe CC and Invision to create mockup and prototype.

UX Designer and Front-end Developer

Nuspay International (Dhaka) July 2014 - Dec 2016

I researched existing banking products and develop new ideas to create wireframes, UI design, prototyping, website design and frontend development for the fintech web.

Graphic Designer

Avery Dennison Bangladesh ltd (Dhaka) Dec 2010 - July 2013

Designed branding tags for the garments products with diverse clients like Walmart, H&M, C&A and make ready for the final production in HP Indigo press. Adobe illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Automation tools have been used.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

University of Oulu (2017 - Present)

Software, Systems and Services Development in Global Environment (GS3D). (Oulu, Finland)

Interaction Design, HCI, Advanced Human Centered Design, Usability testing, Agile Methodology, Research Methods.

Bangladesh University (2011-2014)

BSc in Computer Science and Engineering. (Dhaka, Bangladesh) E-commerce, , Computer Graphic, MIS, Software Engineering, Al.

Graphic Arts Institute (2006 - 2010)

Diploma in Graphic Design and Printing. (Dhaka, Bangladesh)

Graphic Design, Printing, Pre-press, 3D graphic, 2D Graphic.